Marco Di Summa

London, SE3

Email: mdisumma@yahoo.com

Mobile: 07751841415

Website: marcodisumma.com

Passionate about art and technology and driven by new working aspirations, I committed the last four years to turn my interest into a career, building the foundation required to start my journey in the web industry and advance my technical skills within a professional setting.

Recently graduated in web development and looking for an entry level position, my expertise covers graphic design principles, digital media production and web development using the javascript framework and the MERN stack.

PROJECTS

A number of project were developed during the academic studies, including:

Food Delivery Application, 2022

- > Developed a full stack web application using MongoDB, Express.JS, React.JS, Node.JS.
- > Built layouts for a responsive user interface to allow visitors from any device.
- Created the company logo and the graphic assets to enhance brand recognition
- Learned ES6 features as conditional ternary operator and short short-circuit evaluation.
- > Implemented form validation, data manipulation and data retention.
- > Implemented the API endpoints supporting data type recognition and error handling.

Tower Defence Indie Game, 2021

- > Developed user interfaces with the modern javascript frameworks, HTML, and CSS3.
- > Developed the brand identity and a marketing strategy for an indie company.
- > Design graphics assets, game characters and the storytelling to enhance users engagement
- ➤ Learned image optimization, SVG graphic, for optimising web performance.
- > Applied SEO principles, user analytics, email and social media campaigns.

EDUCATION

2020 - 2022	Bachelor of Science in Web Development,	SAE Institute, London
2018 - 2020	Diploma in Graphic Design, Certificate of Achievement - learner awards	WAES Westminster, London
2019 - 2020	Level 2 Award in Creative Media, Certificate of Achievement - learner awards	WAES Westminster, London
1993 - 1998	B Diploma in Fine Art & Design	Liceo Artistico Ripetta, Rome

CODING SKILLS

➤ HTML5	> JSON	Node
➤ CSS3	Javascript	MongoDb
➤ Sass	➤ React	> SVG

SOFTWARE SKILLS

Adobe Creative Suite	➢ Git/GitHub	Visual Studio Code
Illustrator	InDesign	Postman
Photoshop	> Xd	Office Suit

ACADEMIC SKILLS

VOLUNTEER

2019 - 2020	Graphic Design Department	WAES Westminster, London			
WORKING EVERIFINGE					

WORKING EXPERIENCE

2015 - 2018	Private Chef	London, UK
2014 - 2015	Cocomaya	London, UK
2012 - 2014	Tentazioni Restaurant	London, UK
1998 - 2012	Taverna Di Bacco	Rome, Italy

TRANSFERABLE SKILLS

20 years experience as a professional chef starting as owner of the family restaurant and then for a variety of establishments including Michelin starred and private clients:

- > Working under pressure and problem-solving to meet tight schedules;
- > Customer focus and attention to detail to deliver consistently high-quality service;
- > Time management and the ability to multitask in a demanding fast paced environment;
- > Leadership skills in managing kitchen staff and team dynamics;
- > Creativity and adaptability in continuously evolving circumstances;
- > Understanding and implementation of budgeting and business management.

Reference upon request.